OMKAR SHIRISH ACHREKAR

Mumbai, Maharashtra Contact No: +91 9892631152 omkar.achrekarlogs@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/omkar-achrekar-0823

ABOUT ME:

A motivated professional with Data Analysis, Machine Learning and Python development skills with close to two years of experience in data management. I am an excellent team worker and able to take instructions from all levels to build up good working relationships with colleagues & clients. I am keen on learning new things and improving my knowledge, which will help the business grow.

SKILLS:

- Machine Learning Algorithms Implementation in Python and R
- Information Extraction using Python, SQL, R and MS-EXCEL
- Statistical Data Analysis using Python, R and Minitab

WORK EXPERIENCE:

1. Hannover Re, Mumbai, India

May 2020 - Present

Position – Data Quality Manager and Technical Accountant

- Developed a Python script for Technical Accounting process which calculates accounting entries and generates Statement of Account by using data from the database.
- Pro-actively monitor, analyze, track & report on data quality issues
- Understand business processes that are driven by the use of data and to ensure that data lifecycle complies with data quality standards.
- Developed a premium re-calculation automation script in Python to check if the calculations performed By the client are correct.
- Perform data checks using SQL queries to ensure if the data received is conforming to the boundary conditions as well as conditions provided by business underwriters.
- Developed and maintain booking reconciliation reports in PowerBI

2. Data Analyst Intern, Hannover Re, Mumbai

August 2019 – May 2020

Position – Data Analyst Intern

[10 months]

- Successfully designed & developed working Graphical User Interfaces for custom tasks at the office using Python.
- Created Web Scraping Bot to fetch data from set of websites for Non-Life team for travel insurance rates comparison using Python and Selenium module that saved team from weeks of manual work.
- Programmatically cleaned and formatted bordereaux files for upload to SQL database.

PROJECTS:

1. Loan Default Prediction using ML Algorithms in Python

June 2019

'Credit Risk Analysis of XYZ Corporation'

- Performed EDA to extract information and relationship between variables.
- Incorporated Feature selection and Feature Creation.
- Applied different machine learning algorithms and tested the performance of those models on various metrics and selected the best performing algorithm.

2. Customer Retention Analysis using MySQL

June 2019

- Found the number of customers acquired per month.
- Calculated 30days and 90days percentage retention rate of each month. Created stored procedure to automate this process. Using RFM analysis generated important insights about customer segments.

EDUCATION:

• Post-Graduate Program in Data Analytics

Dec 2018 - Jun 2019

Imarticus Learning Institute, Mumbai, MH, INDIA

• Master of Science in Industrial Engineering & Management North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA Aug 2015-May 2018

Bachelor of Engineering in Instrumentation Engineering

Aug 2010-Mar 2014

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, MH, INDIA.